<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown | Esther Siabu Mometolo</title>
    <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Markdown</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/tags/markdown/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Week June 10–16</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📖 &lt;strong&gt;The first exam session is approaching. Time to go all in!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mathematical logic, we took a mock test. It went fairly well, though I made a couple of logical mistakes — I need to read the conditions more carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In analysis, I keep practicing problems on &lt;strong&gt;definite integrals&lt;/strong&gt;. Learned the main techniques: substitution and integration by parts. Lots of practice — and it really helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In programming, we’re reviewing topics from the first semester: data types, loops, and functions. I’ve been solving problems on Codeforces — I really enjoy the format and pacing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Personal Website with Hugo Academic</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/project/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/project/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-a-researcher-have-a-personal-website&#34;&gt;Why Should a Researcher Have a Personal Website?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s academic world, a personal website is more than just a business card. It is a platform for presenting your work, engaging with the research community, and building a personal academic brand. A well-structured website allows you to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📢 Showcase your research and publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 Run a blog or share lab updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔗 Link your profiles on Google Scholar, ORCID, Scopus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎓 Highlight your teaching activities and courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🧠 Increase visibility and citation impact within the scientific community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hugo-academic&#34;&gt;Why Hugo Academic?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is a ready-to-use theme for the static site generator &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, designed specifically for researchers, educators, and students. It offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimalist and professional design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenient structure for displaying publications, projects, courses, and CVs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with GitHub, ORCID, Google Scholar, and other platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High performance and fast loading via static site generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy deployment on GitHub Pages, Netlify, Vercel, and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic publication display&lt;/strong&gt; via BibTeX, JSON, or manual entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profile management&lt;/strong&gt;: photo, research interests, affiliations, social links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects and teaching pages&lt;/strong&gt; with descriptions and visual content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog functionality&lt;/strong&gt; for academic notes, reviews, or open methodology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multilingual support&lt;/strong&gt; for international audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive design&lt;/strong&gt; optimized for both desktop and mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-site-structured&#34;&gt;How Is the Site Structured?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is divided into several key sections, each represented by markdown files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/author&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — profile information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/publication&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — research publications (importable from Zotero or BibTeX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/project&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — descriptions of research projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/post&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — blog posts and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/teaching&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — teaching materials and course pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/_default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — configuration files for menu, links, language, and layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-can-you-host-the-site&#34;&gt;Where Can You Host the Site?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Hugo Academic generates a static site, it can be easily hosted on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt; — free and simple to set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netlify or Vercel&lt;/strong&gt; — automatic CI/CD with free SSL and custom domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University or institutional servers&lt;/strong&gt;, if basic HTML hosting is available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-it-for&#34;&gt;Who Is It For?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool is ideal for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early-career researchers building an online presence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University instructors sharing course materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research groups showcasing collaborative projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graduate school or postdoc applicants creating an academic portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a personal website with Hugo Academic is a powerful way to establish yourself in the academic community. It doesn’t require deep knowledge of web development, yet offers wide opportunities for managing your professional identity online. In the era of open science and digital transformation, such a site is becoming an essential component of a modern academic career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Week June 3–9</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;💻 &lt;strong&gt;Exam prep has officially started!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, we reinforced our understanding of functions. During the lecture, we worked on recursion problems — challenging but fascinating! It’s amazing how a function can call itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In calculus, we began the topic of &lt;strong&gt;function extrema&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m learning how to find critical points and plot graphs. It finally feels like math is coming to life — not just formulas, but real models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In logic, we’re still proving statements. We were given an assignment on mathematical induction — it’s tough so far, but I’m determined to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Week May 27 – June 2</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🧠 &lt;strong&gt;Logic breaks into daily life!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started studying &lt;strong&gt;formal systems and laws of logic&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re learning how to build truth tables and prove tautologies. It feels unusual — I can literally feel my thinking becoming more structured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mathematical analysis, we moved on to &lt;strong&gt;derivatives&lt;/strong&gt;. Practice was quite manageable — the main thing is to remember the rules and keep an eye on the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In programming, we had an independent project — to build a program that calculates text statistics. It didn’t work perfectly at first, but the most important part is: I wrote the code myself, no copy-paste!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Week May 20–26</title>
      <link>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EstherSiabuMometolo.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;This week was all about programming!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In class, we covered the basics of loops and conditional statements in Python. The exercises were quite engaging — especially those that involved processing user input. During the lab, I built a simple calculator for the first time. I made mistakes, fixed them — and that gave me confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mathematical analysis, we started the topic of &lt;strong&gt;sequence limits&lt;/strong&gt;. The theory seems clear at first, but once we got to ε–δ proofs, it became quite a challenge. Fortunately, the professor explained everything with detailed examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I reviewed my notes and started creating flashcards in Anki — might come in handy before the exam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
